Guide to the Edna St. Vincent Millay Papers, 1892-1988
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
- SERIES IV: WORKS BY MILLAY
  - Contributions to Periodicals, etc.
    - "Fugitive," Ainslee's, 1919; (1 item) (Folder 9.23)
    - "Rondel," Ainslee's, 1919; (1 item) (Folder 9.24)
    - "Love Resurgent," Ainslee's, 1919; (1 item) (Folder 9.25)
    - "That Which is Love's," Ainslee's, 1919; (2 items) (Folder 9.26)
    - "Unshriven," Ainslee's, 1919; (1 item) (Folder 9.27)
    - "The Door," Ainslee's, 1919; (2 items) (Folder 9.28)
    - "The Dark Horse" and "Shrine," Ainslee's, 1919; (2 items) (Folder 9.29)
    - "The Seventh Stair," Ainslee's, 1919; (1 item) (Folder 9.30)
    - "Innocents at Large" and "Exiled," Ainslee's, 1919; (2 items) (Folder 9.31)
    - "The White Peacock" and "Elegy Before Death," Ainslee's, 1920; (2 items) (Folder 9.32)
    - "I Only Know that Every Hour..." Reedy's Mirror, 1920; (1 item) (Folder 9.33)
    - "Aria da Capo," Reedy's Mirror, 1920; (1 item) (Folder 25.1 (Oversize))
    - "Nothing in Common," Ainslee's, 1920; (2 items) (Folder 9.34)
    - "Mrs. Dallas Larabee, Sinner," Ainslee's, 1920; (2 items) (Folder 9.35)
    - "The Wild Swans" and others, Vanity Fair, 1920; (1 item) (Folder 26.2 (Oversize))
    - "The Pear Tree," The Living Age, 1921; (1 item) (Folder 9.36)
    - "Sowing the Rue" and others, Current Opinion, 1921; (1 item) (Folder 9.37)
    - "Sentimental Salon," Metropolitan, 1921; (1 item) (Folder 9.38)
    - "The Key" and "Honor Bright," Vanity Fair, 1922; (1 item) (Folder 9.39)
    - Review of Wylie's "Nets to Catch the Wind," Literary Review, 1922; (1 item) (Folder 9.40)
    - "The Barrel," Vanity Fair, 1922; (1 item) (Folder 9.41)
    - "The Barrel," Vanity Fair, 1922; (1 item) (Folder 26.2 (Oversize))
    - "I Said to Beauty..." The Bookman, 1922; (1 item) (Folder 9.42)
    - "Knock Wood" and "The Ballad of the Harp Weaver," Vanity Fair, 1922; (1 item) (Folder 25.2 (Oversize))
    - "Two Lyrics," Yale Review, 1922; (1 item) (Folder 9.43)
    - "To the Liberty Bell," The Liberator, 1922; (1 item) (Folder 9.44)
    - "Diary of an American Art Student..." Vanity Fair, 1922; (1 item) (Folder 9.45)
    - "Tea o' Herbs," A Tree with a Bird in It, 1922; (1 item) (Folder 9.46)
    - "Drama for the Deaf" and "Two Souls..." Vanity Fair, 1923; (1 item) (Folder 9.47)
    - "The Woman Who Would be Moving Beds Around," Vanity Fair, 1923; (1 item) (Folder 9.48)
    - "Madame a Tort," Vanity Fair, 1923; (1 item) (Folder 9.49)
    - "The Platter," Vanity Fair, 1923; (1 item) (Folder 9.50)
    - "Murder in the Fishing Cat," Century, 1923; (1 item) (Folder 9.51)
    - Letter to the Editor regarding Lawson's "Roger Bloomer," New York Times, 1923; (1 item) (Folder 9.52)
    - "Sonnets from and Ungrafted Tree," Harper's, 1923; (2 items) (Folder 9.53)
    - "Say Shibboleth," Vanity Fair, 1923; (1 item) (Folder 9.54)
    - "From a Very Little Sphinx," Harper's, 1923; (2 items) (Folder 9.55)
    - "The Curse," Vanity Fair, 1923; (1 item) (Folder 25.3 (Oversize))
    - "The Pioneer," unidentified newspaper, 1925; (1 item) (Folder 9.56)
    - "Armistice Day Parade," Literary Digest, 1925; (1 item) (Folder 9.57)
    - Yiddish Translations, Der Oifkum, 1927; (1 item) (Folder 9.58)
    - "Fear," Outlook, 1927; (2 items) (Folder 9.59)
    - "Fear," Sacco and Vanzetti National League pamphlet, 1927; (1 item) (Folder 9.60)
    - "Portrait," Saturday Review of Literature, 1928; (1 item) (Folder 9.61)
    - "I Will Give You the Summer" and others, Saturday Evening Post, 1928; (1 item) (Folder 9.62)
    - "The Cameo," New Republic, 1928; (1 item) (Folder 26.2 (Oversize))
    - "When Caesar Fell," New Republic, 1928; (1 item) (Folder 26.2 (Oversize))
    - "On Hearing a Symphony of Beethoven," New Republic, 1928; (1 item) (Folder 26.2 (Oversize))
    - "To a Musician," New Republic, 1928; (1 item) (Folder 26.2 (Oversize))
    - "Lethe," New Republic, 1928; (1 item) (Folder 26.2 (Oversize))
    - "Anguish," New York Herald Tribune Magazine, 1928; (1 item) (Folder 28.2 (Oversize))
    - "Through the Green Forest ," Ladies Home Journal, 1930; (1 item) (Folder 9.63)
    - Love Sonnets, Harper's, 1930; (1 item) (Folder 9.64)
    - "Five Sonnets," Saturday Evening Post, 1930; (1 item) (Folder 9.65)
    - "Four Sonnets," New Republic, 1931; (1 item) (Folder 9.66)
    - "Forest Trees," St. Nicholas, 1931; (1 item) (Folder 9.67)
    - "A Group of New Sonnets," New York Herald Tribune, 1931; (1 item) (Folder 9.68)
    - "Two Sonnets," Harper's, 1931; (1 item) (Folder 9.69)
    - "November," Library Journal, 1932; (1 item) (Folder 9.70)
    - "Not So Far as the Forest," Woman's Home Companion, 1933; (1 item) (Folder 9.71)
    - "Above These Cares," Harper's, 1933; (2 items) (Folder 9.72)
    - "Love Sonnet," Delineator, 1933; (1 item) (Folder 26.2 (Oversize))
    - "A Group of Poems," Saturday Evening Post, 1934; (1 item (clipping)) (Folder 9.73)
    - "A Group of Poems," Saturday Evening Post, 1934; (1 journal)) (Folder 25.6 (Oversize))
    - "Three New Poems," New York Herald Tribune, 1934; (1 item) (Folder 9.74)
    - Foreward to Van Stocum's A Day on Skates, 1934; (1 item) (Folder 9.75)
    - "From a Train Window" and "The Fawn," Delineator, 1934; (1 item) (Folder 9.76)
    - "Apostrophe to Man," Friends Intelligencer, 1934; (1 item) (Folder 9.77)
    - "Conversation at Midnight," Harper's, 1935; (2 items) (Folder 9.78)
    - "Conversation at Midnight," Harper's, 1937; (1 item) (Folder 9.79)
    - "Here in a Rocky Cup," Delineator, 1937; (1 item (clipping)) (Folder 9.80)
    - "Here in a Rocky Cup," Delineator, 1937; (1 journal) (Folder 25.4 (Oversize))
    - "The Princess Recalls her one Adventure," This Week - Philadelphia Record, 1937; (1 item) (Folder 28.2 (Oversize))
    - German Translations, Die Neue Rundschau, 1938; (1 item) (Folder 9.81)
    - "Eight Poems," Poetry, 1938; (1 item) (Folder 9.82)
    - "Say That We Saw Spain Die" and others, Harper's, 1938; (2 items) (Folder 9.83)
    - "The Ballad of Chaldon Down" and four others, Harper's, 1938; (2 items) (Folder 10.1)
    - Eight New Poems, Poetry, 1939; (2 items) (Folder 10.2)
    - "From a Town in a State of Siege," Harper's, 1939; (2 items) (Folder 10.3)
    - Address to the Forum on Current Events, Re: Freedom of Speech, New York Herald Tribune, 1939; (1 item) (Folder 10.79)
    - "Lines Written in Passion..." New York Times, New York Sun, New York Herald Tribune and s.n., 1940; (4 items) (Folder 10.4)
    - "Lines Written in Passion..." New York Times, 1940; (1 item) (Folder 28.4 (Oversize))
    - "Memory of England," New York Times, 1940; (1 item) (Folder 10.5)
    - "Memory of England," New York Times Magazine, 1940; (1 item) (Folder 28.3 (Oversize))
    - Four Sonnets, New York Times Magazine, 1940; (1 item) (Folder 10.6)
    - Four Sonnets, New York Times Magazine, 1940; (1 item) (Folder 28.3 (Oversize))
    - Four Poems, New York Times Magazine, 1940; (1 item) (Folder 10.7)
    - Four Poems, New York Times Magazine, 1940; (1 item) (Folder 28.3 (Oversize))
    - "The President with a Candidate's Face," New York Times, 1940; (1 item) (Folder 10.8)
    - "Young Men and Women..." New York Times Magazine, 1941; (1 item) (Folder 10.9)
    - "When It's Over," Harper's, 1941; (2 items) (Folder 10.10)
    - "Not to be Spattered by his Blood," New York Times Magazine, 1941; (1 item) (Folder 10.11)
    - "Not to be Spattered by his Blood," New York Times Magazine, 1941; (1 item) (Folder 28.2 (Oversize))
    - "The Murder of Lidice," Life, 1942; (1 item (clipping)) (Folder 10.12)
    - "The Murder of Lidice," Life, 1942; (1 journal) (Folder 25.5 (Oversize))
    - "The Murder of Lidice," Saturday Review of Literature, 1942; (1 item) (Folder 10.13)
    - "Thanksgiving, 1942," New York Times Magazine, (1 item) (Folder 10.14)
    - "Thanksgiving, 1942," New York Times Magazine, (1 item) (Folder 28.4 (Oversize))
    - "Nothing if not Enough," Boston Herald Magazine, 1943; (1 item) (Folder 10.80)
    - Speech at New York Times Symposium on the World after the War, 1943; (1 item) (Folder 28.4 (Oversize))
    - "Poem and Prayer..." National Broadcasting Company, 1944; (1 item) (Folder 10.15)
    - "For My Brother Han..." New York Times Magazine, 1945; (1 item) (Folder 10.16)
    - "To the Leaders of the Allied Nations," New York Times Magazine, 1945; (1 item) (Folder 10.17)
    - "To the Leaders of the Allied Nations," New York Times Magazine, 1945; (1 item) (Folder 28.4 (Oversize))
    - "Truck-Garden Market-Day," Good Housekeeping, 1945; (1 item) (Folder 10.18)
    - "New England Spring," Good Housekeeping, 1945; (1 item) (Folder 10.19)
    - "Sonnet," Atlantic, 1946; (2 items) (Folder 10.20)
    - "Ragged Island," Harper's, 1946; (1 item) (Folder 10.21)
    - "Tranquility at Length..." Harper's, 1947; (2 items) (Folder 10.22)
    - "To a Snake," Atlantic, 1947; (1 item) (Folder 10.23)
    - "An Ancient Gesture," Ladies Home Journal, 1949; (1 item) (Folder 10.24)
    - "The Murder in the Fishing Cat," Ellery Queen's Mystery Magazine, 1950; (2 items) (Folder 10.25)
    - "Thanksgiving, 1950," Saturday Evening Post, (1 item) (Folder 10.26)
    - "Thanksgiving, 1950," Saturday Evening Post, (1 item) (Folder 28.4 (Oversize))
    - "If in the Foggy Aleutians," Atlantic, 1950; (2 items) (Folder 10.27)
    - "Christmas Canticle," What's New, 1950; (1 item) (Folder 26.1 (Oversize))
    - "Those Hours When Happy..." Good Housekeeping, 1952; (1 item) (Folder 10.28)
    - "If It Should Rain" and "Sonnet," Good Housekeeping, 1952; (1 item) (Folder 10.29)
    - "God's World," Ladies Home Journal, 1952; (1 item) (Folder 10.30)
    - "A Lovely Light" [condensed], Ladies Home Journal, 1952; (1 item) (Folder 10.31)
    - "The Courage that My Mother Had," Harper's, 1954; (1 item) (Folder 10.32)
    - "Courage," Reader's Digest, 1954; (1 item) (Folder 10.33)
    - "Two Sonnets in Memory," New Republic, 1954; (1 item) (Folder 10.34)
  - Radio Broadcasts
    - "Poem and Pryer for an Invading Army," NBC, 1944; (4 items) (Folder 10.35)
    - "The Murder of Lidice," NBC - final revision, 1942; (1 item) (Folder 10.36)
    - "The Murder of Lidice," NBC - Margaret Cuthbert's correspondence, 1942; (3 telegrams, 11 letter, 1 memo) (Folder 10.37)
    - "The Murder of Lidice," NBC - press releases, 1942; (5 items) (Folder 10.38)
    - "The Murder of Lidice," NBC – clippings, 1942; (23 items (most photocopied) ) (Folder 10.39)
  - Other Material
    - "Invocation to the Muses," read at the National Institute of Arts and Letters ceremonial, 1941; (2 items) (Folder 10.40)
    - Translations of Millay's work to Russian, [1968]; (8 p.) (Folder 10.41)
    - Clippings of Millay's work in newspapers, circa 1950-1979; (9 items) (Folder 10.42)
    - Miscellaneous published work, 1942-1956; (4 items) (Folder 10.43)
- SERIES V: BIBLIOGRAPHICAL MATERIAL
  - Bibliographical lists and notes
    - Bibliography — lists of Vassar College Library, undated; (9 items) (Folder 10.44)
    - Bibliography — lists of Harry Taylor, undated (Folder 10.45)
    - Bibliography — miscellaneous notes, undated (Folder 10.46)
    - Bibliographical notes, undated (Folder 10.47)
  - Book notes and announcements
    - Clippings about publications (Folder 10.48)
    - Book announcements, order cards (Folder 10.49)
    - Hardigut, unpublished Millay novel — correspondence and notes (Folder 10.50)
    - Book Advertisements, 1928 (Folder 10.51)
    - Book Advertisements, 1930-1939 (Folder 10.52)
    - Book Advertisements, 1940- (Folder 10.53)
  - Miscellaneous bibliographical material
    - Dealer Catalog, 1940; (1 item) (Folder 10.54)
    - Auction Catalog, 1948; (2 items) (Folder 10.55)
    - Auction Catalog, 1968; (1 item) (Folder 10.56)
    - Autograph/Dealers Catalogs, 1986; (2 items) (Folder 10.57)
    - Book Jackets from Millay Publications, (6 items) (Folder 13.4)
    - Book Jackets from works about Millay, (6 items) (Folder 13.5)
    - Recordings — Caedmon Catalogs, 1954, 1957, 1959; (3 items) (Folder 10.58)
- SERIES VI: LITERARY REVIEWS AND CRITICISMS
  - Reviews and Criticisms
    - Reviews and Criticisms, 1918-1922; (10 items) (Folder 10.59)
    - Reviews and Criticisms, 1923-1924; (9 items) (Folder 10.60)
    - Reviews and Criticisms, 1925-1926; (4 items) (Folder 10.61)
    - Reviews and Criticisms, 1927; (11 items) (Folder 10.62)
    - Reviews and Criticisms, 1928-1930; (6 items) (Folder 10.63)
    - Reviews and Criticisms, 1931; (10 items) (Folder 10.64)
    - Reviews and Criticisms, 1932-1933; (7 items) (Folder 10.65)
    - Reviews and Criticisms, 1934-1935; (10 items) (Folder 10.66)
    - Reviews and Criticisms, 1936-1938; (9 items) (Folder 10.67)
    - Reviews and Criticisms, 1939-1949; (8 items) (Folder 10.68)
    - Reviews and Criticisms, 1950-1951; (11 items) (Folder 10.69)
    - Reviews and Criticisms, 1952-1953; (12 items) (Folder 10.70)
    - Reviews and Criticisms, 1954-; (7 items) (Folder 10.71)
    - Review — Make Bright the Arrows, The New Yorker, 28 Dec 1940; (1 item) (Folder 10.72)
    - "Anderson, Millay, and Crane," Partisan Review, Nov/Dec 1953; (1 item) (Folder 10.73)
    - Reviews and Criticisms, 1927-1936 (Folder 28.5 (Oversize))
    - Reviews and Criticisms, 1937-1943 (Folder 28.6 (Oversize))
  - Reviews (clippings)
    - Reviews (clippings), 1920-1929 (Folder 10.74)
    - Reviews (clippings), 1930-1939; (10 p.) (Folder 10.75)
    - Reviews (clippings), 1940-1949; (2 items) (Folder 10.76)
    - Reviews (clippings), 1950-1959; (7 items) (Folder 10.77)
    - Reviews (clippings), 1960-1969, undated; (6 items) (Folder 10.78)
  - Other Materials
    - Commentary by Margaret Cuthbert, undated (Folder 11.1)
    - Saturday Review, a letter by Norma Millay, 17 Feb 1951; (2 items) (Folder 11.2)
    - "The Honor Roll in English Poetry,", undated; (1 item) (Folder 11.3)
- SERIES VII: BIOGRAPHICAL AND COMMEMORATIVE MATERIALS
  - Millay Appearances
    - Program — "The Bonds of Interest," The Theatre Guild, 1919; (1 item) (Folder 11.4)
    - Program — "Aria da Capo," Provincetown Players, 1919-1920; (1 item) (Folder 11.5)
    - Millay readings and appearances, 1928, 1934; (2 items) (Folder 11.6)
    - Program — Poetry Society of America Annual Dinner, 1943; (1 item) (Folder 11.7)
  - Articles and Memoirs concerning Millay
    - Dell, Floyd. "Edna St. Vincent Millay finds a Cook,", [1932]; (TS, 16 p.) (Folder 11.8)
    - Van Doren, Carl. "Youth and Wings,", [1923?]; (2 items) (Folder 11.9)
    - "Remembered words of Edna St. Vincent Millay" [NBC Radio Broadcast], 1950; (3 items) (Folder 11.10)
    - Memoir — "A Tribute to Edna St. Vincent Millay" by Allan Ross MacDougall, 1950; (TS, 4 p.) (Folder 11.11)
    - Memoir — "The Woman Poet" by Dorothy Thompson, 1951; (TS, 14 p.) (Folder 11.12)
    - "Vincent at Vassar," Elizabeth Hazelton Haight, 1951; (1 item) (Folder 11.13)
    - "The Woman Poet," Dorothy Thompson, 1951; (1 item) (Folder 28.1 (Oversize))
    - Memoir — "Edna St. Vincent Millay" [West Indian Review], 1952; (TS, 5 p.) (Folder 11.14)
    - "Millay at Steepletop," Vassar Alumnae Magazine, 1957; (1 item) (Folder 11.17)
    - Memoir — "Edna St. Vincent Mially" [Radio Jamaica broadcast] by Walter Adolphe Roberts, 1953; (TS, 6 p.) (Folder 11.15)
    - Memoir — "Tiger Lily" [unpublished] by Walter Adolphe Roberts, undated; (TS, 18 p.) (Folder 11.16)
  - Obituaries and Tributes
    - Obituary — Newsweek, 30 Oct 1950; (1 item) (Folder 12.1)
    - Obituary — Time, 30 Oct 1950; (1 item) (Folder 12.2)
    - Obituaries/Editorials (clippings), [1950]; (6 items) (Folder 12.3)
    - Obituaries and Tributes (clippings) (Folder 12.4)
    - Obituaries and Tributes (clippings) (Folder 12.5)
  - Clippings about Millay
    - David Jackson clippings collection, circa 1975-1988 (Folder 12.6)
    - Ray A. Roberts clippings collection, circa 1940-1974 (Folder 12.6b)
      (contains photograph of Millay and rear of Greenwich Village residence)
    - Harry Taylor clippings collection, 1921-1929; (5 items) (Folder 12.7)
    - Harry Taylor clippings collection, 1930-1939; (4 items) (Folder 12.8)
    - Harry Taylor clippings collection, 1940-1949; (6 items) (Folder 12.9)
    - Harry Taylor clippings collection, 1950-1951; (8 items) (Folder 12.10)
    - Harry Taylor clippings collection, 1952; (7 items) (Folder 12.11)
    - Harry Taylor clippings collection, Jan-Jun 1953; (7 items) (Folder 12.12)
    - Harry Taylor clippings collection, Jul-Dec 1953; (7 items) (Folder 12.13)
    - Harry Taylor clippings collection, Jan-Oct 1954; (9 items) (Folder 12.14)
    - Harry Taylor clippings collection, Nov/Dec 1954; (8 items) (Folder 12.15)
    - Harry Taylor clippings collection, 1955-1958; (9 items) (Folder 12.16)
    - Vassar Library clippings collection, 1920-1929 (Folder 12.17)
    - Vassar Library clippings collection, 1920-1929 (Folder 12.18)
    - Vassar Library clippings collection, 1930-1939 (Folder 12.19)
    - Vassar Library clippings collection, 1930-1939 (Folder 12.20)
    - Vassar Library clippings collection, 1940-1949 (Folder 12.21)
    - Vassar Library clippings collection, 1950-1959 (Folder 12.22)
    - Vassar Library clippings collection, 1950-1959 (Folder 12.23)
    - Vassar Library clippings collection, 1950-1959 (Folder 12.24)
    - Vassar Library clippings collection, 1960-1993, undated (Folder 12.25)
    - Vassar Library clippings collection – scrapbook, 1923-1934 (Folder 12.26)
    - Vassar Library clippings collection – scrapbook, 1923-1938 (Folder 12.27)
    - Vassar Library clippings collection, 1929-1931 (Folder 26.3 (Oversize))
    - Vassar Library clippings collection - oversize - Interview with Henry Kohn, Knickerbocker Press, Sep 1930 (Mapcase — Drawer 37)
    - Vassar Library clippings collection, 1935-1950 (Folder 26.4 (Oversize))
    - Vassar Library clippings collection, 1962 (Folder 26.5 (Oversize))
    - Clippings - Sacco and Vanzetti, 1927 (Folder 12.28)
    - Mounted clippings for The Buck in the Snow, [circa 1892?]); (3 items) (Folder 21.4 (Oversize))
  - Eugen Boissevain
    - Boissevain, Eugen. Excerpts from "The Enjoyment of Living" by Max Eastman, 1948; (1 item) (Folder 12.29)
    - Boissevain, Eugen. Radio script, 15 Apr 1937; (TS, 11 p.) (Folder 12.30)
  - Steepletop
    - Steepletop — Topographical Map of Austerlitz, NY, [1946]; (1 item) (Folder 12.31)
    - Steepletop — Steeplebush, undated; (2 items) (Folder 12.32)
    - Steepletop — Clippings about (Folder 12.33)
  - Tributes to Millay
    - Poem about Millay's work, by Rosie O'Neill, 1931; (TS, 1 p.) (Folder 12.34)
    - Exhibition List — Vassar College Libraries, 1950; (1 item) (Folder 12.35)
    - Program — Exhibit at Cooper Union Library, 1950; (TS, 7 p.) (Folder 12.36)
    - Program — Special Auction for a "Berkshire" Mobile Surgical Unit to England — Allied Relief Benefit, 16 August 1940, (1 item) (Folder 12.37)
    - Dedication of Memorial Room Whitehall Inn, Camden, ME, 18 Jul 1953; (1 item) (Folder 12.38)
    - Edna St. Vincent Millay Society — Correspondence, 1982; (2 items) (Folder 12.39)
    - Tamarack, the Journal of the Edna St. Vincent Millay Society, vol. 1, no. 1, Spring 1981; (1 item) (Folder 12.40)
    - Tamarack, the Journal of the Edna St. Vincent Millay Society, vol. 2, no. 1, Winter 1982/1983; (1 item) (Folder 12.41)
    - Tamarack, the Journal of the Edna St. Vincent Millay Society, vol. 3, no. 1, Fall 1985-Winter 1986; (1 item, 1 letter) (Folder 12.42)
  - Commemorative U.S. Postage Stamp
    - Millay Stamp — "Vassar Views,", (1 item) (Folder 12.43)
    - Millay Stamp — First-day-of-issue stamps, 10 Jul 1981; (32 postcards) (Folder 12.44)
    - Millay Stamp — First-day-of -issue stamps, 10 Jul 1981; (8 envelopes, 1 post office issuance) (Folder 12.45)
    - Millay Stamp — First-day-of-issue stamps, 10 Jul 1981; (5 envelopes) (Folder 12.46)
    - Millay Stamps, (2 1/2 sheets) (Folder 12.47)
    - Millay Stamps, Presentation folder to Vassar College, 10 Jul 1981; (1 item) (Folder 21.1 (Oversize))
    - Millay Stamp — Clippings, [1981]; (3 items) (Folder 12.48)
  - Millay Centennial
    - Millay Centennial, [1992]; (6 items) (Folder 12.49)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Maine, (4 item) (Folder 12.50)
    - Millay portrait by Maxim Kopf, (2 items) (Folder 12.51)
    - Vassar commencement, 1917; (2 items) (Folder 12.52)
- Series VIII: Productions of Works by and about Millay
  - Works Written by Millay
    - "Aria da Capo" — program, 1947; (3 items) (Folder 12.53)
    - "Aria da Capo" — Production information, Henry Street Playhouse, 1955; (2 items) (Folder 13.6)
    - "Aria da Capo" — press release, promotional, 1978; (3 items) (Folder 12.54)
    - "Aria da Capo" — Production information Theatre Marquee, undated; (2 items) (Folder 13.7)
    - "Conversation at Midnight" — programs, information, Civic Playhouse, 1962; (8 items) (Folder 12.55)
    - "Conversations at Midnight" — theatre poster, Civic Playhouse, 1962; (1 item) (Folder 12.56)
    - "Conversation at Midnight" — program, Billy Rose Theatre, 1964; (2 items) (Folder 12.57)
    - "Conversation at Midnight" — brochure, 1964-1965; (1 item) (Folder 12.58)
    - "The King's Henchmen" — advertising booklet, Metropolitan Opera Company of New York, 1927; (1 item) (Folder 12.59)
    - "The King's Henchmen" — program, Camden Hills Theatre, 1953; (2 items) (Folder 12.60)
    - "The King's Henchman" — program, production information, Bel Canto Opera, 1976; (4 items) (Folder 12.61)
    - "The King's Henchmen" — program, Fulton Opera House, undated; (1 item) (Folder 12.62)
    - "The King's Henchmen" — galley sheet and typescript used by Deems Taylor, circa 1927; (2 items) (Folder 27.1 (Oversize))
  - Productions about Millay and her works
    - "An Evening with Millay," Lincoln Center, 1975; (4 items) (Folder 12.63)
    - "An Evening with Millay," Lincoln Center, 1975; (4 items) (Folder 12.64)
    - "Irrevocably Yours,", 1981; (2 items) (Folder 12.65)
    - "Millay at Steepletop" film announcement, 1978; (1 item) (Folder 12.66)
    - "A Lovely Light" — program, Hudson Theatre, 1960; (1 item) (Folder 12.67)
    - "A Lovely Light" — program, Mayfair Theatre, undated; (2 items) (Folder 12.68)
    - "A Lovely Light" — Clippings (Folder 12.69)
    - "A Lovely Light" — Promotional, 1960 (Folder 12.70)
    - "A Lovely Light" — Programs, (5 items) (Folder 12.71)
    - "A Lovely Light" — Programs, Hudson and TV Theatres, (2 items) (Folder 12.72)
  - Musical Adaptations of Millay's Poetry
    - "Thursday,", 1923; (1 item) (Folder 12.73)
    - "From a Very Little Sphinx,", 1926; (1 item) (Folder 27.3 (Oversize))
    - "Afternoon on a Hill" and "Horse Shoe,", 1928; (2 items) (Folder 12.74)
    - "The Return from Town,", 1928; (1 item) (Folder 12.75)
    - "My Candle...,", 1928; (1 item) (Folder 12.76)
    - "The Little Tavern,", 1929; (1 item) (Folder 12.77)
    - "Elaine,", 1931; (1 item) (Folder 12.78)
    - "God's World,", 1932, 1933; (2 items) (Folder 12.79)
    - 3 Songs — "Rain Comes Down," "Mariposa," and "One, Two Three,", 1940; (1 item) (Folder 27.3 (Oversize))
    - "Recuerdo,", 1941; (1 item) (Folder 27.4 (Oversize))
    - "Ballad of the Harpweaver," as adapted by Edith Evans Braun, 1941; (several items) (Folder 27.2 (Oversize))
    - "Face of God,", 1954; (1 item) (Folder 12.80)
    - "The Road to Avrille,", 1971; (1 item) (Folder 27.4 (Oversize))
    - "The Spring and the Fall,", 1971; (1 item) (Folder 27.4 (Oversize))
- Series IX: Photographs
  - Photographs of Millay's Youth (circa 1893-1914)
    - Snapshot [ref. no. 6.190], circa 1893; (1 item) (Folder 14.1)
    - Portrait, circa 1905; (2 items) (Folder 14.2)
    - Portrait [ref. no. 6.306], circa 1905; (2 items) (Folder 14.3)
    - Snapshots, at Chelmsford, MA, circa 1905-1909; (6 items) (Folder 14.4)
    - Snapshot [ref. no. 6.215], circa 1908; (3 items) (Folder 14.5)
    - Snapshot [ref. no. 6.189], 1909; (1 item) (Folder 14.6)
    - High School Portrait [ref. no. 6.213], 1909; (2 items) (Folder 14.7)